13 Creepiest Places In The World
13.
Cat Island
Tashirojima is an island located off the Eastern
coast of Japan about 200 miles north of Tokyo.
At 1.2 square miles, the island, is slightly
smaller than the size of Central Park in New
York.
While I’m sure Central Park has some stray
cats, it doesn’t compare to Cat Island,
as Tashirojima is known, where the cats outnumber
the people 6 to 1.
The reason for the cat mania is the island
was inhabited by people growing silkworms
and they had cats to catch mice so they couldn’t
eat the silkworms.
Also cats are believed to be good luck that
will bring money.
Some people believe the cats saved the island
from being destroyed by the 2011 Tsunami.
As you might expect, dogs are not allowed
on the island.
And while cats are cute, when you have 600
of them staring at you, it might get a little
creepy.
12.
The Skeleton Lake India
Looking for a peaceful vacation by the lake?
You might want to avoid The Lake of Roopkund,
unless you find scattered human skeletons
relaxing.
Known as skeleton lake, the lake and its disturbing
occupants were originally discovered in World
W ll by British soldiers who thought they
were the bodies of Japanese troops.
Later testing revealed the remains to actually
be dated to approximately 850AD.
While the mass deaths of the more than 200
people were originally a mystery, scientists
now believe they were all killed by a single
hail storm, which left the peculiar round
wounds to the tops of their heads and shoulder
bones.
11.
Overtoun Bridge
If you're the kind of person who likes taking
your dogs on vacation with you, then you might
want to avoid Overtoun Bridge in Milton, Scotland.
Apparently the bridge has an unknown, rather
menacing influence over our furry companions
that causes them to jump off of it, often
to their death.
The 50ft drop has claimed the lives of at
least 50 dogs in 50 years, with the most deadly
stretch being a six month period during which
time five dogs leapt to their death.
While scientists who have studied the area
believe the dogs could be jumping in response
to the scent of minks below the bridge, the
theory still leaves many unanswered questions
such as why all the dogs jump around the exact
same spot - the right side at the least two
parapets.
The odd deadly effect of the bridge may not
be particular to canines as in 1994 a local
man named Kevin Moy killed his baby boy - said
to be only two weeks old - by throwing him
off the bridge at about the same spot, saying
he believed the child was the anti-Christ.
10.
Centralia Pennsylvania
Dubbed "one of the creepiest places in the
USA", the town of Centralia in Pennsylvania
was once home to over 1,000 people but is
now a hazardous ghost town.
The towns street are blocked to vehicles and
the outskirts plastered with warning signs
telling people to stay out or face possible
death from asphyxiation or from falling through
the ground into the fiery depths below, as
it was condemned by the government in 1992.
It all started with what was meant to be a
harmless fire set intentionally to burn the
towns landfill in 1962, however all did not
go as planned as the landfill was also an
old strip-mine pit that was unfortunately
connected to an intricate maze of underground
mining tunnels filled to the brink with coal.
Despite the townsfolk being able to extinguish
the above ground fire, the extensive coal
supply and vast tunnel system have kept the
underground fire burning for 54 years and
there is believed to be enough coal to keep
it going for another 250 years.
While the underground fire did not cause the
townspeople immediate concern, it's dangers
became apparent when in 1981 a 12 year old
boy fell through a hole that suddenly appeared
in his back yard and would of certainly died
had a 14 year old boy not been there to quickly
pull him out.
While there are about a dozen inhabitants
who refuse to leave the dangerous town, the
government plans to bulldoze their houses
after they die in order to prevent future
inhabitants.
9.
Akodessewa Fetish Market in Togo
If you enjoy waking up on a Saturday morning,
grabbing a coffee and taking a nice lingering
walk through your local market, you may want
to stay far away from the Akodessewa Fetish
Market in Lome, Togo where you would almost
certainly be scared from the market experience
for life - literally.
Instead of finding crafts, fresh vegetables
or flowers you'll find "many different kinds
of animal heads" including crocodiles, cats,
monkey's, snakes and numerous kinds of birds
at this market.
Describing what they do at the market for
its customers, a voodoo healer says they will,
'grind up the heads with herbs and then put
the mixture on the fire.
This leaves us with a black powder.
We cut the person's chest or back three times
and then rub the powder into the flesh.'
8.
Poveglia Island aka Plague Island in Italy
Considered by locals to be the 'most haunted
place on Earth', few people have set foot
on Poveglia Island since the 1960s.
In fact, photographer Mike Deere had a hard
time finding a local willing to take him to
the 18 acre island.
When he finally did find a willing local,
he says it cost a significant price and the
apparently brave local man refused to step
foot on the island or even wait there for
him, instead opting to come back in a few
hours to pick him up.
The reason for this perhaps superstitious
but justifiable behaviour from Venetians,
the islands morbid history.
The island was once used as a quarantine for
people suffering from infectious disease and
became a mass burial site for plaque victims
sent there to be burned.
If that's not gruesome enough, in the 1920's
it then became a mental hospital where, according
to locals, a deranged doctor conducted experiments
on patients before taking his own life by
jumping off the asylum's bell tower.
In total, it's estimated that around 150,000
people died on the island.
7.
Snake Island in Brazil
Even someone who loves snakes wouldn't want
to visit Brazil's Snake Island, Ilha de Queimada
Grande.
The 4.6 million square foot island is home
to over 4,000 golden lancehead viper snakes.
With venom five times stronger than that of
other snakes, the golden lancehead viper is
the world's deadliest snake.
The last inhabitants of the island was the
lighthouse keeper and his family but they
were all tragically killed by the predators,
their bodies found scattered across the island
as they presumably were trying to run away
when their house was overtaken.
After numerous human deaths, visiting the
island was banned by the Brazilian government,
with the exception of a few scientists who
have been granted permission to study the
snakes annually, and the Brazilian navy who
must visit the island on occasion to tend
to the lighthouse.
6.
Island of Dolls
A popular attraction for thrill seekers looking
for a scare is Mexico's Doll Island.
An eerie sight to see, the island is draped
with thousands of sinister looking dolls.
According to the legend of this peculiar decor,
Julian Santana Barrera who was the caretaker
of the island found a little girl drowned
in a nearby canal.
Shortly after, he found a doll that was presumably
hers and guilt ridden for not having saved
her, he hung the doll to show her spirit respect
and support.
Haunted by the spirit of the little girl,
Julian claimed to hear her tormented screams
and continued to collect dolls and hang them
in the trees to try and please her spirit.
According to the Isla de las Munecas (Island
of Dolls) website, "After 50 years of collecting
dolls and hanging them on the island, Julian
was found dead, drowned in the same spot where
the girl had died."
5.
Anderlecht Veterinary Surgical School
Known as 'The Horror Labs', an old veterinary
school in Brussels, Belgium which has been
abandoned since 1990 has been described as
something straight out of a horror movie.
While the surrounding buildings have been
sold and developed into luxury apartments,
there still sits one sole derelict building
with gruesome contents.
One British urban explorer who dared to enter
the eerie building known for its animal experiments
said, 'It's like being in some crazed professor's
laboratory containing all manner of grotesque
animal organs and body parts.'
4.
Jatinga near Assam India
A small scenic village in Assam, India called
Jatinga seems quite peaceful and pleasant
but once a year it becomes a dark and sinister
place.
Every year between September and November
shortly after sunset - between 7 and 10pm
- hundreds of birds plummet to their death
at the same strip of land which is about 1.5km
long and 200 metres wide.
Perhaps equally disturbing, are the villagers
themselves who look forward to the annual
event and not only attack the birds that survive
the plummet with catapults or bamboo sticks
but also created a festival around the bird
suicides called the Jatinga Festival.
3.
Catacombs of Paris
Deep below the bustling streets of Paris,
below the metro, even below the sewer system
lies 200 miles of eerie tunnels.
The narrow, dark passages are home to the
bones of over six million humans, bones that
fill the walls from top to bottom.
Parisiens originally dug the intricate tunnel
system to use the ground materials for building
the city upwards.
However when the cemeteries became overcrowded
by the 18th century, the stench of dead bodies
and outbreak of disease caused by rotting
bodies becoming exposed, gave the tunnels
a new use.
In 1768 in the dead of night, the bodies were
moved from the cemeteries to the tunnels in
carts covered with cloth, while priests chanted
for the dead as they passed.
The catacombs newest arrivals came during
the Revolution, as those who perished were
taken directly to the deathly tunnels.
2.
Herxheim
Herxheim Germany was apparently a place to
stay far away from during the collapse of
the European farming society some 7,000 years
ago.
As archaeologists studied the 7,000 year old
bones found there, they discovered the grotesque
history of the region as it became apparent
to them that the inhabitants of the time participated
in cannibalism.
Apparently not even children or unborn babies
were safe from the horrific fate, as even
their bones showed obvious signs such as "chew
marks" and marks normally found on a butchered
animal.
It's even likely some of the victims were
spit-roasted.
According to researchers the sheer number
of victims, which is likely around 1,000,
indicates the cannibalism was not a last resort
in times of famine, but rather either done
in victory celebrations after the victims
were killed in war or as a ritual sacrifice
during which the victims were slaughtered
and consumed.
1.
Aokigahara Forest aka Suicide Forest - Japan
While the name of one Japan forest, Aokigahara
meaning 'Sea of Trees' seems harmless enough,
the mysterious forest has a much more sinister
reputation as it is known as suicide forest.
While there is a long history of people going
to the morbid forest to commit suicide, the
numbers have gone up drastically in the last
two decades, as it went from about 30 suicides
a year prior to 1990 to 108 by 2004.
Presumably in an effort to decrease the phenomenon,
local authorities have stopped making the
annual death toll public, however police records
for 2010 showed 247 suicide attempts, with
54 of them resulting in death.
The deadly forest is now so well known for
its fatalities it is now decorated with signs
aimed at trying to dissuade visitors from
killing themselves.